var generalQuestions = [
  {
    question: "In what country does the Suez Canal reside?",
    answer: "egypt",
    // was wondering why you had a key value pair for status? Doesn't appear to be used in the script.js file, i love that you are using an object to represent each question and answer. You can see the advantages it brings adding properties like status and whatever else you want moving forward in your application.
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Whats the symbol for iron?",
    answer: "fe",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "In what city is the Golden Gate Bridge?",
    answer: "san francisco",
  },
  {
    question: "In what city is broadway?",
    answer: "new york",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "In what city is Notre Dame cathedral?",
    answer: "paris",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Approximately how many minutes does is take for light from the sun to reach earth (please type out number)",
    answer: "eight",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Which planet is closest to the sun?",
    answer: "mercury",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What element makes of the majority of the sun?",
    answer: "hydrogen",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "How many billion years old is the sun (please type of number)?",
    answer: "five",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What is the top selling spice in the world?",
    answer: "pepper",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What is the most widely eaten fish in the world?",
    answer: "herring",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "On what continent did pineapple originate?",
    answer: "south america",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What nutty legume accounts for one sixth of the world's vegetable oil production?",
    answer: "peanut",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What nation produces 2/3's of the world's vanilla?",
    answer: "madagascar",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What falling fruit supposedly inspired Isaac Newton to write the laws of gravity?",
    answer: "apple",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What sticky sweetener was traditionally used as an antiseptic ointment for cuts and burns?",
    answer: "honey",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What continent is subject to the world's largest ozone hole?",
    answer: "antarctica",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What is the most malleable metal?",
    answer: "gold",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What Italian astronomer invent the thermometer in 1592?",
    answer: "galileo",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Who averaged one patent for every three weeks of his life?",
    answer: "thomas edison",
    status: false
  },
];
var sportsQuestions = [
  // I noticed you made 3 variables all representing an array of question and answer pairs. The fact that they've been separated by variable means there might be an oppunity to refactor. We could just make another key value pair for our questions like, questionType or category. something like
  // {
  //   question: "Who was the only heavyweight champion to finish his boxing career with a perfect record (49-0)",
  //   answer: "rocky marciano",
  //   category: "sports"
  // }
  // In this way our code becomes more modular. I don't have to instantiate a new global variable to create different categories.
  {
    question: "Who was the only heavyweight champion to finish his boxing career with a perfect record (49-0)",
    answer: "rocky marciano",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Which national team introduced 'Total Football' at the 1974 FIFA World Cup in Germany?",
    answer: "holland",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Which male tennis player lost a record 4 US Open singles finals in 1976, 1978, 1980, and 1981?",
    answer: "bjorn borg",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What lefty has won the most Grand Slam singles titles in mens tennis?",
    answer: "rod laver",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What is the highest score a judge can award in Figure skating? (please type out number)",
    answer: "six",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "In which city is the Maracana stadium?",
    answer: "brazil",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "In 1988, who became the first boxer to have won world championships in five different weight class?",
    answer: "sugar ray leonard",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What sport is played by the Minnesota Twins?",
    answer: "baseball",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Boca Juniors are from which South American country?",
    answer: "argentina",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "In 1981, Susan Brown was the first female competitor in which sporting event?",
    answer: "boat race",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "In judo, the Black belt is the highest, what colour is the second highest?",
    answer: "brown",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Which was the first Asian country to hold a F1 Grand Prix?",
    answer: "japan",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Which sport was reintroduced to the Seoul Olympics after an absence of 64 years?",
    answer: "tennis",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Who fought Mohammed Ali in The Rumble In The Jungle?",
    answer: "george forman",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "In cricket what is the maximum number of people that can be on the field when the ball is in play? (please type out number)",
    answer: "seventeen",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Who was the first golfer to win the US Masters five times?",
    answer: "jack nicklaus",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Which swimmer won 7 gold medals at the 1972 Olympic games?",
    answer: "mark spitz",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "A southpaw boxer leads with which hand and off which foot?",
    answer: "right",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "In which sport did Irina Rodnina win 23 World, Olympic, and European gold medals?",
    answer: "figure skating",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Who became the 1st non-European to win the Tour de France cycle race?",
    answer: "greg lemond",
    status: false
  },
];
var geographyQuestions = [
  {
    question: "In which country were the Hanging Gardens of Babylon located?",
    answer: "iraq",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What is the capital of New Zealand",
    answer: "wellington",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Which animal is responsible for the most human deaths in Africa?",
    answer: "hippo",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name given to the active volcano located in Sicily?",
    answer: "mount etna",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "In which US state is the Grand Canyon located?",
    answer: "arizona",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "In which country would you find the Port of Alexandria?",
    answer: "egypt",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What is the largest island in the world?",
    answer: "greenland",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the sea that lies between Israel and Jordan?",
    answer: "the dead sea",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What occured first, the Stone Age or the Bronze Age?",
    answer: "the stone age",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Which is warmer, the North Pole or the South Pole?",
    answer: "the north pole",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "In which US state is Las Vegas situated?",
    answer: "nevada",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Which country is Jakarta the capital city of?",
    answer: "indonesia",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What event is measured by the Richter scale?",
    answer: "earthquake",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "The largest sand island in the world is in Australia, what is its name??",
    answer: "fraser island",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "In which city would you find the city of Kremlin?",
    answer: "moscow",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What is the former name of Thailand?",
    answer: "siam",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What US state is Madison the capital of?",
    answer: "wisconsin",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What is the capital of Japan?",
    answer: "tokyo",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "What is the largest Scandinavian country?",
    answer: "sweden",
    status: false
  },
  {
    question: "Which river flows through the Grand Canyon?",
    answer: "colorado",
    status: false
  },
];
